Wael Zoaiter

Address: Damascus, Syria

Date of birth: 17/4/1995

Phone: +963 937 991 254

Email: wael.zoaiter@gmail.com

LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/wael-zoaiterPortfolio:https://wael-zoaiter-portfolio.netlify.com/

Brief Introduction:

I'm **Full-Stack Developer** with three years of hands-on experience efficiently coding websites and applications using **React Js**, **React Native** and **Node js**.

Building state-of-the-art, user-friendly websites and applications is a passion of mine, And I actively seek out new technologies and stay up-to-date on industry trends and advancements.

Education:

Bachelor Degree in Computer Engineering

Damascus University, Syria Expected Graduation: 2020

Experience:

Full-Stack Web Developer

Company: *Stowk*

Type: *Part time - Remote* **Date**: 04/2020 *to* Present

Responsibilities:

- Conducting requirements gathering and validation as a part of collaboration for the high-profile
 progressive web application using **Node js** that helped to develop clear, unambiguous technical
 requirements and establish consistent feed-back loop.
- Implementation of the set of new API endpoints related to the mission-critical internal web application, that provided critical connectivity channel for distributed functionality and increase system cohesion keeping manageable code complexity.
- Optimizing legacy data storages and search queries for the high-volume external web app utilizing **MongoDB.**

Full-Stack Web Developer

Company: at ITDBase

Type: Part time - Remote

Date: 03/2020 to Present

Responsibilities:

- Developed User Interface (UI) applications and professional web applications using HTML, XHTML, CSS2/CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Node JS, React JS, Express JS, Socket IO, Bootstrap, JSP, Mongo DB.
- Experience in building MEAN applications using MongoDB, Express.JS, Angular-JS, Node-JS, creating Web services components of Restful Web services to interact with UI Interfaces using REST API with Node-JS, Express-JS and installing client side dependencies.

Front-End Web Developer

Company: Forsa.sy

Type: Full time and Support **Date:** 08/2019 to Present

Responsibilities:

- Worked on an **Agile Development Team** to deliver regular updates.
- Used Web services (**RESTful**) for transmission of large blocks of **JSON**.
- Familiar with creating Custom Reusable **React Components Library**.
- Developed responsive website that could be served to **desktop**, **Tablets** and **mobile** users.
- Involved designing in web pages using HTML 5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SASS, **React.js, Redux**.

Mobile Application Developer

Company: *iEducate.co*

Type: *Support and Consultant* **Date:** 08/2019 *to* Present

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for develop the Admin Dashboard using React js.
- Responsible for develop new mobile application on Android and IOS using React Native.
- Took initiative in learning **React native** and went on to successfully develop various features.
- Created Reusable react **presentation** and container **components**.

Web Developer

Company: Web Injaz Co - Full time

Date: 03/2018 to 07/2019

Responsibilities:

- Design, develop and test HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery and React.JS that meets web standards.
- Designed CSS templates for use in all pages on the website.
- Applied optimization techniques to reduce **page size** and **load times** to enhance user experience.
- Developed user interface by using the React JS, Redux for SPA development.

Volunteer:

Graphic Designer at RBCs Team

Date: 06/2014 to 11/2016

Tech: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe illustrator

Technical Skills:

Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, Typescript, JSP, JSON, DOM, Agile (Scrum, Kanban).

JavaScript Libraries: JQuery, React.js, Bootstrap, Express.js, Nest.js, Node.js, Socket IO.

Database: MySQL, MSSQL, PLSQL, MongoDB.